NALLELY ROBLEDO,

Computer Science & Data Analytics

Guadalupe N.L. México | +52 8182038768 | nallelyrobledo190@gmail.com

Profile

An skilled professional in engineering and data analysis with 3 years of working experience across different industries.

My main strengths are the application of statistical tests, data exploration, and the implementation of Machine Learning for the segregation and classification of structured data.

Work Experience

Siemens · Santa Catarina. N.L. México

Jul 2022-Currently

Data Analyst

- Identified trends and patterns related to deviations in the manufacturing process through data exploration and statistical tests application.
- Performed business cases through data analysis and visualization creation to support data-driven decision-making.
- Developed infrastructure for optimal Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) of data sources, with a focus on measurement equipment.
- Achieved early detection of abnormal patterns in the production process by creating real-time visual insights for Statistical Process Control (SPC).
- Enhanced transparency in material flow within the release process by creating a visualization integrating information from SAP (Hana) and other sources.
- Transformed data capture processes through the development of applications using Microsoft Power Apps and Power Automate.

Dal-Tile · San Pedro G.G. N.L. México

Mar 2021-Jul 2022

Order Management Analyst

- Handling B2B customer sales orders and purchase orders.
- Thoroughly review special prices, discounts, quotations, etc.
- Manage intercompany customer orders with sales, logistics, and accounting departments.
- Track and meet KPIs: fill rate, on-time delivery & customer satisfaction.
- Enter orders into ERP and CRM systems.

Karcher · Santa Catarina N.l. México Supply Chain Internship

Ene 2018 -Jul 2019

- Sending payment receipts to suppliers, tracking shipping guides, and updating records.
- Preparation of reports on equipment maintenance, shipment tracking, and updating import information.
- Verification of supplier invoices against warehouse receipts and management of domestic guides.
- Support in Service Coordination: Issuance and tracking of shipping guides, as well as warranty ticket tracking with service providers.
- Support in Vendor Management: Vendor registration in systems such as Laserfiche, tracking and verification of accounts payable.

Education

San Nicolas de los Garza N.L. Mex *Chemical Sciences, UANL*Bachelor in Engineering

Aug 2015 - May 2020

San Nicolas de los Garza N.L. Mex *Physics and Mathematics, UANL* Master in Data Science

Sep 2022 - Jul 2024

Certificates

ITESM

Nov 2023

Certificate of Citizen Data Scientist

SCRUMstudy Certificate of Scrum Master

Oct 2022

Skills

Computer / Data Analytics

Microsoft Office
MS SQL Server
Python / R
Power Apps + Automate
Tableau / Power BI
Cloud Services
UX design

Interpersonal Skills

Analytical Skills Multitasking Adaptability Communication Skills

Others

Bootcamp of Efficiency and Technological Inovation in Siemens

2023 - 2024

Freelance Software Solutions Contributor.

2020 - 2021

Tutoring students of lower educational grades in Sciences as Mathematics and Stadisthics.

2017 - 2018